ELIAS SPECTOR-ZABUSKY

607-592-5831 | elias.spector.zabusky@gmail.com | Brooklyn, New York

in linkedin.com/in/elias-sz | Ogithub.com/ColdWeatherBoyy | ● Portfolio: http://www.eliassz.com

SUMMARY

Web developer, digital native, and musician working with the MERN stack, with an interest in backend development, product work, databases, and AI. Graduate of Columbia's Coding Bootcamp with experience in project management, operations, and the arts. Strong skills in creative problem-solving, collaboration, partnered with a work ethic centered on adaptability, meticulousness, and camaraderie. Analytically minded with a knack for aiding decision-making.

PROJECTS

FRAiME | GITHUBLINK/ | DEPLOYLINK/

Co-Founder and Lead Developer. eCommerce site in development; leverages OpenAI's API for Dall-E and DaVinci. Users will generate bespoke art that they can then order prints of. Future features include selectable preprompts, finetuning prompts, and print API connection.

- Co-Designed and sketched out full backend architecture, frontend features, and design.
- Coded majority of CRUD routes, database models, and backend server, to be integrated once MVP is settled.
- Built with MERN stack, with MongoDB, Next.is and Styled Components.

Dada Art Museum | github.com/ColdWeatherBovy/dada-museum | dada-museum.herokuapp.com

Lead Developer and UI Designer. Proof of concept showcase piece. Co-designed and implemented UI for a museum's homepage; built Current Exhibits and Featured Artist section; collaborated on other homepage code.

- Designed and implemented system for randomizing art with calls to the Art Institute of Chicago's API.
- Built with Node, React, Express, and Chakra UI.

Vite React Template | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy/vite-template | template-test-1.herokuapp.com

Lead Engineer. A template for MERN applications, with basic authorization capabilities baked in using JSON Web Token and a connection to a MongoDB preconfigured. Testable with an app like Insomnia.

Built with MERN stack, with MongoDB, React Router, DotEny, Bcrypt, and JSON Web Token.

EDUCATION

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY, NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Jan. 2023 – Apr. 2023

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

HARVARD BUSINESS SCHOOL ONLINE

Feb. 2023 – Apr. 2023

Certificate in Business Analytics

BROWN UNIVERSITY, PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND

2011 - 2015

Bachelor of Arts in Theatre Arts and Performance Studies

Phi Beta Kappa; T. Carpenter Elocution Award

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, GraphQL, NoSQL

Frontend: React, Chakra UI, Next.is, Styled Components, Handlebars, Vite

Backend: MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Mongoose, Sequelize, MySQL

Development Tools: VS Code, Insomnia, Chrome Dev Tools, Git, GitHub

Other: MS Excel, Google Analytics, Shopify, Chat GPT prompting

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PROFESSIONAL MUSICIAN

Nov. 2015 – Present

Band-member, producer, songwriter, and/or arranger for a few NYC-based bands. www.stolenjars.com/

DIGITAL CONTENT AND MERCHANDISE MANAGER

ROBIN BARON DESIGN; NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Led product-related operations for an interior designer's eCommerce business and acted as admin of the Shopify site. Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop strategic plans for growth.

Spearheaded the product upload for site launch, bringing the project up to speed in 6 weeks. In line with growth roadmap, managed a team of 8-10 freelancers in the upload of 12,500+ SKUs from ~40 vendors.

INDEPENDENT EDITOR AND CONSULTANT, NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Nov. 2020 - Jan 2023

Offered editorial and writing services for resumes and cover letters, helping earn multiple clients' new jobs.